What's wrong?
Did you bite your tongue?
It's my tooth...
It's wobbly...
Don't touch it!
What should I do?
You've got a permanent tooth coming in from the bottom,
so just leave it alone.
Do you want your rice as porridge?
No, it'll be fine if I eat slowly.
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
Cultural
Festival
Daikichi!
Hi.
W-What?!
Look, there's my drawing!
Kaga Rin
Rin-chan, your dad always comes to these things, huh?
Yeah.
Although he's not my dad...
He's not?!
Huh. It's great.
You know what?!
Rin-chan's the best at drawing in Class B!
You don't say...
I bet you could become a mangaka!
No way!
I'm sure you could!
Papa!
Over here!
Sorry I'm late.
This guy with the clothes and the hair is her dad?
How handsome!
Lucky!
He's so tall!
You know what? Sayaka-chan's father is 31, the same age as you, Daikichi!
Seriously?!
Really? What a happy coincidence.
My papa does modeling!
Wow!
Now, Sayaka!
Just a little.
When I was younger...
I think I may have seen you before in my company's catalog...
Really?!
Excuse me.
If you don't mind my asking, what's the name of your company?
That may be me!
I'm much obliged!
Cheerful guy, isn't he?
Now I'm embarrassed!
These days, I'm a manager for the same agency.
Oh, really?
It seems like kind of a waste...
It's the kind of work where you can't really predict the hours or income,
so when my daughter was born, I had to stop.
Oh...
At that time, I was drinking almost every night and complaining about work...
Hey, Mi-chan!
Nabe-chin! Long time no see!
We were classmates.
We're both from the same neighborhood.
He's got a boy in Class A.
This is Rin-chan's father, Daikichi-san.
He's the same age as we are.
Oh yeah? Nice to meet you!
Likewise.
These two are the type that protect their kids...
Daikichi!
I'm a butcher.
My shop's on the corner of the shopping district.
Rin and I often get take-out croquettes there.
Really? That makes me feel good!
Me too! Me too!
I know, I know!
I made fellow father-friends...
In a sense, the world may be wider here...
Hello.
Hello!
It's suddenly turned cold, hasn't it?
Yes.
It seems the kids are already in the gym.
I just hope he has his jacket on...
Yeah...
Nitani
Kouki
Wow, he's quite the artist.
Really?
I mean, you can tell he took a lot of time on it...
You know what, all the kids are in the gym already.
Seriously?!
Crap! My teacher's gonna get mad at me!
Something I don't like about boys...
Oh, how adorable! How many months?
Almost 10 months.
I love babies!
Makes me feel nostalgic...
Well, my kid had the flu last week...
I'm sorry I've kept you...
Oh, really? That must've been rough.
Not at all!
Is it that season already?
With that, they have to stay home for two days even if the fever's down, right?
So it doesn't spread...
Yeah, but I sent him to school right after his temperature went down.
Well, what else could you do?
You don't want to get fired.
Right, and he was getting better, so the virus was probably weakened.
Oh, I'm sure...
Besides, even if he did pass it on, nobody would ever know who did it.
Shall we go?
Um... What those mothers were talking about kind of hit home.
And that makes me even more depressed...
Like about work. I can relate.
Yeah, I know...
When it gets cold out, I become a nervous wreck.
But Kouki, the way he is...
Put your pajamas on now!
But once winter passes and it starts to get warm out,
I'll finally breathe a sigh of relief.
Daikichi!
Daikichi, I'll go get my satchel, so wait here!
Are you two dummies?!
Kouki, your nose!
It's cold in the gym, which is why I told you to wear your jacket!
And don't run in the halls!
Okay!
I said don't run!
Kouki's baby teeth are already starting to come out, huh?
We live in an apartment complex,
so throwing teeth onto the roof doesn't work.
Note: Lower baby teeth are thrown onto the roof as a charm
to make the permanent bottom teeth come in straight
Recently, he hasn't been listening to me at all.
Well, I don't have room to talk.
I used to wear the absolute minimum,
and I'd run down the stairs full speed, skipping every other step...
I'd wolf down lunch, drink milk in one gulp...
It feels really weird telling kids not to do everything that I did.
You did all that, Daikichi-san?
I think it's relatively normal for a boy...
Anyway, I don't think of Kouki as just another kid.
S-Sorry...
But if you were like that too, Daikichi-san,
it makes me feel a little relieved.
What's wrong? Walk with Kouki!
I don't want to!
Then let's split into a boys' team and a girls' team!
Is Rin-chan's face a little flushed?
I think she has a fever.
It might get higher.
That's a lot more flushed than usual!
Well, it's not the flu.
For now, please have all of the family members wear a mask.
Sure!
That's good news, huh?
Yeah!
Huh?
Are you done?
Yeah... I don't feel right around here...
The doctor said it was the stomach flu, so you don't have to force yourself.
Yeah... I feel kind of...
Rin!
W-Washbowl!
Rin does?!
Call an ambulance right away!
No, I already had her checked out by a doctor and we got medicine,
but she won't take it!
Her fever keeps climbing higher and she looks like she's miserable...
I bet you had her wear light clothes!
Right now, that's irrelevant!
Did you try mixing the medicine in with juice?
You always drank it right away if it was mixed with something sweet.
I'll try it.
Thanks, Mom.
Here, just try a little.
It's sweet.
Come on, just a spoonful.
Daikichi...
I'm sorry for coming so early.
How's Rin-chan?
I'm sorry!
May I come in?
Daikichi, what's with that hair?
Sure...
She doesn't have the flu, but...
Kouki, go watch TV over there.
All right!
Quietly!
She finally fell asleep a little while ago...
Her fever keeps rising...
And it seems like she's not able to sleep much...
She's not sweating at all...
Has she been able to drink?
I was told to at least give her sports drinks,
but she won't eat or drink anything!
I don't know what to do...
W-What?!
You can't get flustered!
The adult has to stay calm and tell her it's going to be all right.
It's hard.
I've never seen Rin like this before.
It's not hard! You can do it!
When a child is in real trouble,
an adult who will help needs to be by their side.
Rin-chan will be fine as long as you're there, Daikichi-san.
Rin-chan...
Kouki-kun's mom...
You must be thirsty.
Want to try sucking on some ice?
How's that?
It feels good.
Rin! You're up?!
I'm sorry, I was in the bathroom.
Daikichi-san!
Sorry.
In a little while, suck on some more ice.
If you have it all at once, you'll surprise your tummy.
Okay.
I just put something sweet and yummy in the fridge for later.
I'm sorry. You'll be late for work, won't you?
Rin-chan is really doing her best.
If you're here for her, she'll be okay, Daikichi-san.
Right. Thank you.
You too, Kouki. Thank you.
Sure.
Sorry. I might have to take off tomorrow, too.
If something comes up, give me a call.
Got it.
Sorry for the trouble...
What are you talking about?!
Please, leave everything to me!
Thank you.
Can you eat a little bit?
Yeah...
When you have a cold, you get to eat all these sweets.
Later.
You'll get better after a bit more rest.
Why Rin?
If I'd gotten it, it'd be nothing to me.
Damn it!
Damn it! Damn it!
Yeah?
Daikichi!
Hey!
Kouki!
How do you feel, Rin-chan?
Does it hurt anywhere?
I'm okay.
I'm going to make you some yummy rice gruel now, okay?
Her fever's gone up again since this afternoon.
It's all right.
Even normal temperatures are lower in the morning and rise in the afternoon.
But earlier it was higher than 39 degrees...
Here, put this in the pot.
Sure.
Daikichi...
Water...
That looks good...
I made it for you too, Daikichi-san.
Daikichi! Rin wants water!
Got it!
Kouki, I don't want you catching it, so stay in this room, okay?
I don't mind getting it.
You can't mean that!
Thanks.
Kouki-kun, thank you.
Kouki, when you're here, Rin feels totally at ease.
Yeah...
Here, Rin-chan. Eat a little bit.
Don't worry. When Kouki gets sick, he eats this too.
It's specially made gruel that helps you get better fast.
Kouki-kun does too?
That's right.
Whenever he ate this, his cold was gone before I knew it.
It's good!
Daikichi!
Rin! Are you better?
Yeah. I feel fine.
I'm hungry!
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
Will you tell your mom thank you for the other evening?
She looked after Rin, so...
Hey, can I go home with you guys?
That again?!
Your mom has to be the one who picks you up from here!
See, my mom is sick in bed with a cold.
What?! Are you serious?!
Let the winds of heaven
Blow through the paths among the clouds
And close their gates.
Then for a while I could detain
These messengers in maiden form.
Thank you for listening!
I'm Rin.
My tooth is falling out.
It will fall out soon, Daikichi.
Don't worry, Daikichi.
The next story, and the last story, is "The First Step."
Episode 11
The First Step
Bye Bye.